
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>SigNoz</title>
      <link>https://signoz.io/blog</link>
      <description>SigNoz is an open-source observability tool powered by OpenTelemetry. Get APM, logs, traces, metrics, exceptions, &amp; alerts in a single tool.</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://signoz.io/tags/launch-week/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      
  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/improvements-to-logs-search-and-filter</guid>
    <title>Logs Search &amp; Filter - Taking Quick Analysis of Logs to the Next Level</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/improvements-to-logs-search-and-filter</link>
    <description>Searching and filtering for logs to debug issues is one of the top critical workflows any developer uses. We have gathered feedback from our users and shipped some important features that focus on speeding up log searches, refining the filtering process, and enhancing the overall log analysis experience.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>product</category><category>launch-week</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/insights-into-signoz-latest-features</guid>
    <title>Insights into SigNoz’s Latest Features - A Conversation with Ankit, CTO of SigNoz</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/insights-into-signoz-latest-features</link>
    <description>We sat down with Ankit, CTO and co-founder at SigNoz to get his insights on the product’s developments and what&#39;s on the horizon. He shared valuable perspectives on how SigNoz is enhancing the user experience, focusing on customer feedback, and building new features.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>product</category><category>launch-week</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/introducing-alerts-history-and-scheduled-maintenance</guid>
    <title>Introducing Alerts History and Scheduled Maintenance - Enhancing Alert Management in SigNoz</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/introducing-alerts-history-and-scheduled-maintenance</link>
    <description>Whenever an alert is triggered, developers want to examine its history. By offering a comprehensive view of past alerts, the Alerts History feature allows teams to identify patterns, understand key contributors to alerts, and make informed decisions about how to resolve issues more efficiently.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>product</category><category>launch-week</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/introducing-anomaly-detection-for-smarter-alerts</guid>
    <title>Introducing Anomaly Detection - Smarter Alerts for Dynamic Metrics</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/introducing-anomaly-detection-for-smarter-alerts</link>
    <description>Anomaly Detection will enable users to create smarter alerts based on dynamic metrics, moving beyond traditional fixed-threshold alerts. By detecting deviations from expected patterns, Anomaly Detection will help you stay informed about critical issues without getting overwhelmed by irrelevant alerts.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>product</category><category>launch-week</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/introducing-correlation-of-signals</guid>
    <title>Introducing Correlation - Bringing Infra/APM Metrics and Logs Together in SigNoz</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/introducing-correlation-of-signals</link>
    <description>With SigNoz, you can monitor logs, metrics, and traces under a single pane of glass. We&#39;ve enhanced the ability to correlate signals by linking infrastructure metrics with logs and logs with APM metrics, helping you resolve issues more efficiently.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>product</category><category>launch-week</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/signoz-is-soc2-type2-and-hipaa-compliant</guid>
    <title>SigNoz is now SOC2 Type 2 and HIPAA Compliant</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/signoz-is-soc2-type2-and-hipaa-compliant</link>
    <description>We’re thrilled to announce that SigNoz is now SOC 2 Type II and HIPAA compliant.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>product</category><category>launch-week</category>
  </item>

    </channel>
  </rss>
