
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>SigNoz</title>
      <link>https://signoz.io/blog</link>
      <description>SigNoz is an open-source observability tool powered by OpenTelemetry. Get APM, logs, traces, metrics, exceptions, &amp; alerts in a single tool.</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://signoz.io/tags/jaeger/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      
  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/aws-xray-vs-jaeger</guid>
    <title>AWS X-Ray vs Jaeger - key features, differences and alternatives</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/aws-xray-vs-jaeger</link>
    <description>Both AWS X-Ray and Jaeger are distributed tracing tools used for performance monitoring in a microservices architecture. Jaeger was originally built by teams at Uber and then open-sourced in 2015. On the other hand, AWS X-Ray is a distributed tracing tool provided by AWS specifically focused on distributed tracing for applications using Amazon Cloud Services.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/datadog-vs-jaeger</guid>
    <title>DataDog vs Jaeger - key features, differences and alternatives</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/datadog-vs-jaeger</link>
    <description>DataDog is an enterprise-level monitoring and security tool. On the other hand, Jaeger is an open-source tool focused on end-to-end distributed tracing for microservice architecture. DataDog is a full-stack paid APM tool, whereas Jaeger is free and open-source..</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/distributed-tracing-jaeger-cassandra</guid>
    <title>Distributed tracing using Jaeger with Cassandra</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/distributed-tracing-jaeger-cassandra</link>
    <description>With microservices becoming popular, tracing is increasingly more important in debugging production software. In this post, we take you through a step by step guide on setting up Jaeger over Kubernetes with Cassandra storage.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Distributed Tracing</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/distributed-tracing-jaeger</guid>
    <title>Jaeger distributed tracing - complete guide</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/distributed-tracing-jaeger</link>
    <description>Jaeger is a popular open-source tool used for distributed tracing in a microservice architecture. See a demo ride-sharing application reporting its traces through Jaeger...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Distributed Tracing</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-microservices</guid>
    <title>Using Jaeger for your microservices</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-microservices</link>
    <description>Jaeger is a popular open-source tool used for distributed tracing in a microservice architecture. In a microservice architecture, a user request or transaction can travel across hundreds of services before serving what a user wants.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Distributed Tracing</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-elastic-apm</guid>
    <title>Jaeger vs Elastic APM - key differences, features and alternatives</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-elastic-apm</link>
    <description>Jaeger is an open-source end-to-end distributed tracing tool for microservices architecture. On the other hand, Elastic APM is an application performance monitoring system which is built on top of the ELK Stack...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-newrelic</guid>
    <title>Jaeger vs New Relic - Key differences, use-cases and alternatives</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-newrelic</link>
    <description>Jaeger and New Relic are tools used in the application monitoring and observability domain. While Jaeger is open-source, New Relic is a SaaS vendor. Jaeger is suited for distributed tracing and New Relic...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-opentracing</guid>
    <title>Jaeger and OpenTracing - Key concepts, use-cases and alternatives</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-opentracing</link>
    <description>Jaeger and OpenTracing are both open-source projects aimed to solve pain-points of distributed tracing. But the scope of the projects are completely different. While Jaeger is an end-to-end distributed tracing tool..</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-prometheus</guid>
    <title>Jaeger vs Prometheus - Side by Side Comparison [Updated for 2025]</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-prometheus</link>
    <description>Both Jaeger and Prometheus are popular open-source application performance monitoring tools. While Jaeger is an end-to-end distributed tracing tool, Prometheus is used as a time-series database for monitoring metrics. Let&#39;s dive in to explore their key features and differences.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category><category>Prometheus</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-signoz</guid>
    <title>Jaeger vs SigNoz - Taking distributed tracing to the next level</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-signoz</link>
    <description>Thinking of using Jaeger for distributed tracing? But wait, there is a much better alternative. SigNoz provides advanced capabilities for distributed tracing along with metrics and ...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category><category>SigNoz</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-tempo</guid>
    <title>Jaeger vs Tempo - key features, differences, and alternatives</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-tempo</link>
    <description>Both Jaeger and Grafana Tempo are tools aimed at distributed tracing for microservice architecture. Tempo supports multiple open-source instrumentation standards, while Jaeger supports OpenTracing APIs..</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-zipkin</guid>
    <title>Jaeger vs Zipkin - Choosing the Right Tracing Tool</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/jaeger-vs-zipkin</link>
    <description>Compare Jaeger and Zipkin, two popular distributed tracing tools. Learn their features, strengths, and how to choose the right one for your microservices architecture.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/blog/opentelemetry-vs-jaeger</guid>
    <title>OpenTelemetry and Jaeger | Key Features &amp; Differences [2025]</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/blog/opentelemetry-vs-jaeger</link>
    <description>OpenTelemetry is a broader, vendor-neutral framework for generating and collecting telemetry data (logs, metrics, traces), offering flexible backend integration. Jaeger, on the other hand, is focused on distributed tracing in microservices...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>Tools Comparison</category><category>Jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/guides/can-jaeger-show-metrics</guid>
    <title>Can Jaeger Show Metrics? - How to Monitor and Visualize Performance</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/guides/can-jaeger-show-metrics</link>
    <description>Discover Jaeger&#39;s metrics capabilities, learn how to enable and visualize performance data, and integrate with other monitoring tools for comprehensive system insights.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>faq</category><category>jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/guides/how-to-implement-jaeger</guid>
    <title>How to Implement Jaeger? - A Step-by-Step Guide for Developers</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/guides/how-to-implement-jaeger</link>
    <description>Learn how to implement Jaeger, the open-source distributed tracing system, with this comprehensive guide for developers. Master setup, instrumentation, and best practices.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>faq</category><category>jaeger</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://signoz.io/guides/what-database-does-jaeger-use</guid>
    <title>What Database does Jaeger Use - Elasticsearch vs Cassandra</title>
    <link>https://signoz.io/guides/what-database-does-jaeger-use</link>
    <description>Discover the primary databases Jaeger uses for distributed tracing. Compare Elasticsearch and Cassandra to choose the best option for your deployment.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>hello@signoz.io (SigNoz Inc)</author>
    <category>faq</category><category>jaeger</category>
  </item>

    </channel>
  </rss>
